¬
{Far_Below_Average_Intelligence}	Far Below Average Intelligence
{Below_Average_Intelligence}	Below Average Intelligence
{Average_Intelligence}	Average Intelligence
{Naturally_Intelligent}	Naturally Intelligent
{Natural_Genius}	Natural Genius
{Far_Below_Average_Charisma}	Far Below Average Charisma
{Below_Average_Charisma}	Below Average Charisma
{Average_Charisma}	Average Charisma
{Good_Charisma}	Good Charisma
{Great_Charisma}	Great Charisma
{Far_Below_Average_Energy}	Far Below Average Energy
{Below_Average_Energy}	Below Average Energy
{Average_Energy}	Average Energy
{Naturally_Lively}	Naturally Lively
{Naturally_Energetic}	Naturally Energetic
{ICE000}	Dull/Uncharismatic/Languorous
{ICE000_desc}
This man's lack of natural ability makes him unlikely to become great or renowned, but he may yet make a fine subordinate to a greater general, or even a governor of some distant land. But who knows the future? He may rise above his inborn limitations to great glory, and honour. Some men make up for their weaknesses with strengths such as courage, steadfastness, or loyalty. Others become hopeless failures--forgotten, if lucky, and hated, if unfortunate.
{ICE000_effects_desc}-1 Chivalry, +4 Authority
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's Low Intelligence means it will be difficult for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's Low Charisma means it will be difficult for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's Low Vitality means it will be difficult for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{ICE001}	Dull/Uncharismatic/Vigorous
{ICE001_desc}
This man's lack of innate intellectual capability or social skills means that he must make the best use of his drive and passion to overcome his weaknesses. Through study or practice, he may become better than someone with inborn ability. He might make a great general who leads his men from the front, rather than giving orders from the rear. Or he might turn his energy to darker deeds or more useless pursuits.
{ICE001_effects_desc}-2 Chivalry, +5 Authority, +1 Command, +1 Defence, +1 Piety, +1 Loyalty, +1 Troop Morale
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's Low Intelligence means it will be difficult for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's Low Charisma means it will be difficult for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's High Vitality means it will be easier for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{ICE010}	Dull/Charismatic/Languorous
{ICE010_desc}
This man's lack of innate intellectual capability, health and drive means that he must get what he wants through his influence over others. Men like this may inspire or entice with their words, and can accomplish much with little physical action. He might make a great governor, or an inspiring general. Or maybe not.
{ICE010_effects_desc}+2 Chivalry, +5 Authority
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's Low Intelligence means it will be difficult for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's High Charisma means it will be easier for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's Low Vitality means it will be difficult for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{ICE011}	Dull/Charismatic/Vigorous
{ICE011_desc}
This man's low intellectual ability is somewhat compensated for by his social skills and his vitality. There is such a thing as being too smart for one's own good, and this man knows how to comport himself around others. He may not make a great tactician or math genius, but hard work and the right connections can carry one far in life.
{ICE011_effects_desc}+1 Chivalry, +4 Authority
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's Low Intelligence means it will be difficult for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's High Charisma means it will be easier for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's High Vitality means it will be easier for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{ICE100}	Sharp/Uncharismatic/Languorous
{ICE100_desc}
This man's intelligence is offset by poor social skills and vitality. This type of man may be bookish or reserved, and might be best suited for tasks that do not require teamwork or great athleticism. He could still make a great general, through tactical genius or careful planning. He could become an able administrator, double-checking his budgets and figures to eliminate waste or corruption. Or he could be undercut by a treacherous underling or slain in battle.
{ICE100_effects_desc}-1 Chivalry, +3 Authority
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's High Intelligence means it will be easier for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's Low Charisma means it will be difficult for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's Low Vitality means it will be difficult for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{ICE101}	Sharp/Uncharismatic/Vigorous
{ICE101_desc}
This man's low social skills make him ill-suited for public speaking or politics. But his intelligence and vitality could be put to use as a wily general or efficient governor. He might not be the most inspiring leader, but men are better served by an able leader than a flashy one.
{ICE101_effects_desc}-1 Chivalry, +4 Authority, +1 Command
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's High Intelligence means it will be easier for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's Low Charisma means it will be difficult for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's High Vitality means it will be easier for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{ICE110}	Sharp/Charismatic/Languorous
{ICE110_desc}
This man has the intelligence and charisma, but may lack the will that leads to the full application of these innate abilities. He may not be lazy, per se--He could be of poor health. But one way or another, this man's weak life force will hinder him in his life.
{ICE110_effects_desc}+1 Chivalry, +4 Authority
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's High Intelligence means it will be easier for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's High Charisma means it will be easier for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's Low Vitality means it will be difficult for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{ICE111}	Sharp/Charismatic/Vigorous
{ICE111_desc}
There are few men who excel in all they do. This man may be one of those few. At least, he lacks any glaring weakness in his intellect, charisma, or vitality. This gives him a head start, but it does not mean he has already won the race.
{ICE111_effects_desc}+2 Chivalry, +5 Authority, +1 Command, +1 Piety
\nIntelligence - How well the character processes and retains information. \nThis man's High Intelligence means it will be easier for him to advance in Intelligence-based skills such as Management, Mathematics, and Tactics.\n\nCharisma - How well the character gets along with people or gets them to do what he says. This can be through garnering respect, love, or just intimidation. \nThis man's High Charisma means it will be easier for him to advance in Charisma-based skills such as Influence, Leadership, or Inspiring speeches.\n\nVitality - How much ambition, energy, and health the character possesses.\nThis man's High Vitality means it will be easier for him to advance in Vitality-based skills such as Brave, or Bloodthirsty, or gain additional HitPoints through HaleAndHearty.
{Adept_Agent}Adept Agent
{Adept_Agent_desc}Proven capable of seeing what needs to be seen, without being seen himself.
{Adept_Agent_effects_desc}+2 to agent's skill, +2 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Adept_Spy}Adept Spy
{Adept_Spy_desc}A true adept in the ways of subterfuge and espionage, and one of the realm's finest set of eyes.
{Adept_Spy_effects_desc}+4 to agent's skill, +4 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Agitator}Agitator
{Agitator_desc}Able to inspire malcontent feelings within an audience.
{Agitator_effects_desc}+2 to popularity (improves public order)
{Aspiring_Commander}Aspiring Commander
{Aspiring_Commander_desc}This man has shown he has a sound set of battle tactics, and the ability to command men.
{Aspiring_Commander_effects_desc}+2 Command
{Awkward_Diplomat}Awkward Diplomat
{Awkward_Diplomat_desc}Though he has been schooled in the arts of diplomacy, it would seem he did not quite grasp all of the lessons he was taught.
{Awkward_Diplomat_effects_desc}-1 Influence
{Awkward_Speaker}Awkward Speaker
{Awkward_Speaker_desc}This man is not graceful with words, making his speeches somewhat of an ordeal to suffer.
{Awkward_Speaker_effects_desc}-1 Authority, -1 Morale for all troops on the battlefield
{Bean_Counter}Bean Counter
{Bean_Counter_desc}Some early success in this budding merchant's career suggest he could become a true asset.
{Bean_Counter_effects_desc}+1 Finance
{Bilingual}Bilingual
{Bilingual_desc}Speaks both his faction's tongue, plus that of the locale he grew up in.
{Bilingual_effects_desc}+1 Influence
{Bold_Barterer}Bold Barterer
{Bold_Barterer_desc}A healthy track record of moving into other markets make this merchant a reliable source of income.
{Bold_Barterer_effects_desc}+2 Finance
{Budding_Bureaucrat}Budding Bureaucrat
{Budding_Bureaucrat_desc}Seems quite capable at managing the affairs of a settlement, enough to entrust to govern efficiently.
{Budding_Bureaucrat_effects_desc}3% bonus on all trade income, +1 to law (improves public order)
{Can_Tell_a_Tale}Can Tell a Tale
{Can_Tell_a_Tale_desc}Able to hold an audience well enough when trying to get a story or message across.
{Can_Tell_a_Tale_effects_desc}+1 to law (improves public order)
{Capitalist}Capitalist
{Capitalist_desc}Now that he has achieved sole control over his market, this merchant is learning how best to keep it to himself.
{Capitalist_effects_desc}+1 Finance
{Commercial_Conqueror}Commercial Conqueror
{Commercial_Conqueror_desc}This man doesn't break into new markets, he simply takes them. 
{Commercial_Conqueror_effects_desc}+3 Finance
{Competent_Sailor}Competent Sailor
{Competent_Sailor_desc}This man has proven he at least has the seafaring legs required to survive a scrap at sea.
{Competent_Sailor_effects_desc}+1 Command at sea
{Conspicuous}Conspicuous
{Conspicuous_desc}Not quite as sneaky and cunning as he'd like to believe he is.
{Conspicuous_effects_desc}-1 from agent's skill
{Daft_Dealer}Daft Dealer
{Daft_Dealer_desc}Has already failed in an attempt to put another merchant out of business.
{Daft_Dealer_effects_desc}-1 Finance
{Devoid_of_Subtlety}Devoid of Subtlety
{Devoid_of_Subtlety_desc}This man simply has no idea about how to prevent everyone within line of sight from knowing what he is up to.
{Devoid_of_Subtlety_effects_desc}-3 from agent's skill
{Dogmatic_Beliefs}Dogmatic Beliefs
{Dogmatic_Beliefs_desc}When one grows up being subjected to only one faith, accepting the others is always very difficult.
{Dogmatic_Beliefs_effects_desc}-1 Influence
{Easy_Target}Easy Target
{Easy_Target_desc}His clumsy attempts at taking down his rivals suggest he would be an easy target himself.
{Easy_Target_effects_desc}-2 Finance
{Faction_Leader}Faction Leader
{Faction_Leader_desc}This man is the leader of one of the world's major powers, and commands respect and obedience as a result.
{Faction_Leader_effects_desc}+1 Command, +2 Authority, +3 to personal security (improves the chances of detecting and foiling assassination attempts)
{Fine_Officer}Fine Officer
{Fine_Officer_desc}This man has developed a sound understanding of navigation and naval tactics, making him a worthy officer.
{Fine_Officer_effects_desc}+2 Command at sea
{Good_Diplomat}Good Diplomat
{Good_Diplomat_desc}Understands both how to act, and how to read while at the diplomacy table.
{Good_Diplomat_effects_desc}+2 Influence
{Good_with_Money}Good with Money
{Good_with_Money_desc}Displayed an uncommon understanding of how to work with money from an early age.
{Good_with_Money_effects_desc}+1 Finance
{Great_Admiral}Great Admiral
{Great_Admiral_desc}So fierce and capable is this experienced naval commander, most pirates mention his name in nervous whispers.
{Great_Admiral_effects_desc}+4 Command at sea
{Great_Commander}Great Commander
{Great_Commander_desc}This man boasts a proud legacy of decisive command in battle, reliable and effective.
{Great_Commander_effects_desc}+4 Command
{Great_Speaker}Great Speaker
{Great_Speaker_desc}Capable of inspiring tears or cries of joy when addressing a group of men on a serious matter.
{Great_Speaker_effects_desc}+1 to law (improves public order)
{Heir_Apparent}Heir Apparent
{Heir_Apparent_desc}As the next leader of his people, this man is already an individual of immense importance.
{Heir_Apparent_effects_desc}+1 Command, +1 Authority, +2 to personal security (improves the chances of detecting and foiling assassination attempts)
{Incompetent_Commander}Incompetent Commander
{Incompetent_Commander_desc}This man has a knack for making a meal of things when attempting to take command.
{Incompetent_Commander_effects_desc}-2 Command
{Inconspicuous}Inconspicuous
{Inconspicuous_desc}Able to blend in most places without drawing attention to himself.
{Inconspicuous_effects_desc}+1 to agent's skill, +1 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Incredibly_Boring}Incredibly Boring
{Incredibly_Boring_desc}This man couldn't excite a prisoner with a tale of freedom - he is simply incredibly dull to talk to.
{Incredibly_Boring_effects_desc}-2 Authority, -2 Morale for all troops on the battlefield
{Inefficient_Administrator}Inefficient Administrator
{Inefficient_Administrator_desc}Sloppy with paperwork and government issues, this man makes a poor governor.
{Inefficient_Administrator_effects_desc}5% penalty on all trade income
{Inspirational_Speaker}Inspirational Speaker
{Inspirational_Speaker_desc}When this man speaks, other men become better than themselves, ready to live or die for his cause.
{Inspirational_Speaker_effects_desc}+2 to law (improves public order)
{Instigator}Instigator
{Instigator_desc}Often the first man to say something to start a heated debate, but not always the one to finish it.
{Instigator_effects_desc}+1 to popularity (improves public order)
{Leader_of_the_Mob}Leader of the Mob
{Leader_of_the_Mob_desc}The kind of man who can champion the people with words, their belief in his ability and ideals, absolute.
{Leader_of_the_Mob_effects_desc}+2 Authority, +4 to popularity (improves public order), +2 to unrest (has a negative effect on public order)
{Legal_Expert}Legal Expert
{Legal_Expert_desc}If there's a legal loophole in a contract or trade agreement, this man will spot and exploit it.
{Legal_Expert_effects_desc}+2 Finance
{Legal_Nouse}Legal Nouse
{Legal_Nouse_desc}Has enough understanding of the law to both avoid trouble, and to sometimes cause a little without risk.
{Legal_Nouse_effects_desc}+1 Finance
{Legendary_Admiral}Legendary Admiral
{Legendary_Admiral_desc}Sailors throughout the known world speak of this old sea dog with reverence and awe. 
{Legendary_Admiral_effects_desc}+5 Command at sea
{Legendary_Commander}Legendary Commander
{Legendary_Commander_desc}Countless victories have made this man is a legendary commander, respected by both his own troops and those that oppose him.
{Legendary_Commander_effects_desc}+5 Command
{Logistician}Logistician
{Logistician_desc}Completely organised when it comes to military logistics, enough so to maintain a huge fighting force without issue.
{Logistician_effects_desc}+3 Morale for all troops on the battlefield, +20% to Movement Points (gives armies the ability to forced march)
{Logistics_Expert}Logistics Expert
{Logistics_Expert_desc}An expert at ensuring his forces are well supplied and in good condition.
{Logistics_Expert_effects_desc}+2 Morale for all troops on the battlefield, +15% to Movement Points (gives armies the ability to forced march)
{Loyalty_Starting_Value}Loyalty Starting Value
{Loyalty_Starting_Value_desc}Sets starting loyalty value.
{Loyalty_Starting_Value_effects_desc}+5 Loyalty
{Market_Controller}Market Controller
{Market_Controller_desc}Time spent with a monopoly has allowed this man to discover new avenues of how to expand, and exploit it.
{Market_Controller_effects_desc}+2 Finance
{Master_Spy}Master Spy
{Master_Spy_desc}No door can hold this man, no secret can remain safe. A true master spy, and a key asset to your intelligence network.
{Master_Spy_effects_desc}+5 to agent's skill, +5 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Master_of_Diplomacy}Master of Diplomacy
{Master_of_Diplomacy_desc}This man is so cunning at leading a conversation, he can make people agree to things before they realise what they have done.
{Master_of_Diplomacy_effects_desc}+5 Influence
{Mercantile_Genius}Mercantile Genius
{Mercantile_Genius_desc}Able to make money without even trying, this man was born to work with coin.
{Mercantile_Genius_effects_desc}+3 Finance
{Monopolist}Monopolist
{Monopolist_desc}Years of mastering the art of cornering a market has produced both healthy profits, as well as some murderously jealous peers.
{Monopolist_effects_desc}+3 Finance,-1 from personal security (increases the chances of falling victim to assassination)
{Multilingual}Multilingual
{Multilingual_desc}Can speak fluently in several languages, making his work in foreign courts much more effective.
{Multilingual_effects_desc}+2 Influence
{Natural_Born_Merchant}Natural Born Merchant
{Natural_Born_Merchant_desc}Has a rare talent to evaluate the true worth of any given deal, and reaps the ample benefit as a result.
{Natural_Born_Merchant_effects_desc}+2 Finance
{Natural_Spy}Natural Spy
{Natural_Spy_desc}Understands espionage innately and completely. A man of mystery to be sure.
{Natural_Spy_effects_desc}+3 to agent's skill
{Not_Dogmatic}Not Dogmatic
{Not_Dogmatic_desc}Growing up in an area without a truly dominant religion has made this man sensitive to what offends followers of different faiths.
{Not_Dogmatic_effects_desc}+1 Influence
{Open_Purse}Open Purse
{Open_Purse_desc}His pathetic attempts at economic warfare suggest he will one day fall victim to a more shrewd merchant.
{Open_Purse_effects_desc}-3 Finance
{Open_to_all_Religions}Open to all Religions
{Open_to_all_Religions_desc}Offers total respect to the religious beliefs of those he encounters, even if they are totally contrary to his own.
{Open_to_all_Religions_effects_desc}+3 Influence
{Pathetic_Commander}Pathetic Commander
{Pathetic_Commander_desc}This man could clutch defeat from the jaws of victory.
{Pathetic_Commander_effects_desc}-3 Command
{Perfect_Politician}Perfect Politician
{Perfect_Politician_desc}Has an iron-clad grip on the world of politics, and is a master of dealing with and understanding other peoples.
{Perfect_Politician_effects_desc}-2 Loyalty, +2 Authority
{Political_Animal}Political Animal
{Political_Animal_desc}Few savour the world of politics but this man has a love for the deals and schemes of kingdoms.
{Political_Animal_effects_desc}-1 Loyalty, +1 Authority
{Political_Promise}Political Promise
{Political_Promise_desc}Showing interest and promise in the deadly games of politics.
{Political_Promise_effects_desc}+1 Authority
{Poor_Administrator}Poor Administrator
{Poor_Administrator_desc}Not one to entrust a complicated civil problem with.
{Poor_Administrator_effects_desc}3% penalty on all trade income
{Poor_Diplomat}Poor Diplomat
{Poor_Diplomat_desc}Has made a meal of several meetings that had no real reason to be so problematic or troublesome.
{Poor_Diplomat_effects_desc}-2 Influence
{Poor_Speaker}Poor Speaker
{Poor_Speaker_desc}Lacks any sort of flair or conviction when delivering a speech.
{Poor_Speaker_effects_desc}-1 Authority
{Poor_Spy}Poor Spy
{Poor_Spy_desc}Far from the most cunning agent you will ever recruit, he has failed on more than one act of subterfuge
{Poor_Spy_effects_desc}-2 from agent's skill
{Promising_Commander}Promising Commander
{Promising_Commander_desc}This man has shown at least a basic grasp of field tactics.
{Promising_Commander_effects_desc}+1 Command
{Promising_Diplomat}Promising Diplomat
{Promising_Diplomat_desc}Seems to be able to hold himself in the correct manner during diplomacy.
{Promising_Diplomat_effects_desc}+1 Influence
{Promising_Strategist}Promising Strategist
{Promising_Strategist_desc}Has shown an aptitude for strategy during his studies.
{Promising_Strategist_effects_desc}+1 Command
{Promising_Tactician}Promising Tactician
{Promising_Tactician_desc}Not only does this man remember what he has been taught about tactics, he understands the theory as well.
{Promising_Tactician_effects_desc}+2 Command when ambushing, +1 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Proven_Commander}Proven Commander
{Proven_Commander_desc}This man has proven himself to be able to command men in battle very effectively.
{Proven_Commander_effects_desc}+3 Command
{Provoker}Provoker
{Provoker_desc}Can rouse a group of downtrodden folk with words of strength and determination that are not too flowery or noble.
{Provoker_effects_desc}+1 Authority, +3 to popularity (improves public order), +1 to unrest (has a negative effect on public order)
{Quietly_Observant}Quietly Observant
{Quietly_Observant_desc}Has always been one to notice things without others knowing he was there.
{Quietly_Observant_effects_desc}+1 to agent's skill
{Religiously_Intolerant}Religiously Intolerant
{Religiously_Intolerant_desc}Intolerant enough of other religions to the point he uses their names as derogatory terms.
{Religiously_Intolerant_effects_desc}-2 Influence
{Respects_other_Religions}Respects other Religions
{Respects_other_Religions_desc}He may find the basis of some religions to be flawed, but he will not make the mistake of telling people so.
{Respects_other_Religions_effects_desc}+2 Influence
{Robber_Baron}Robber Baron
{Robber_Baron_desc}Even merchants from the Far East speak this man's name with reverence and awe. A true financial genius.
{Robber_Baron_effects_desc}+4 Finance
{Shady_Dealer}Shady Dealer
{Shady_Dealer_desc}Can't seem to reach a trade agreement without trying to commit fraud or worse.
{Shady_Dealer_effects_desc}-2 Finance
{Skilled_Bureaucrat}Skilled Bureaucrat
{Skilled_Bureaucrat_desc}This man is able to deal with complicated administrative issues effectively.
{Skilled_Bureaucrat_effects_desc}5% bonus on all trade income, +2 to law (improves public order)
{Slightly_Crooked}Slightly Crooked
{Slightly_Crooked_desc}Growing up in a relatively lawless place has taught this man some undesirable business practises.
{Slightly_Crooked_effects_desc}-1 Finance
{Spy}Spy
{Spy_desc}Espionage is an art to this man. He has succeeded on enough missions to justify his growing confidence.
{Spy_effects_desc}+3 to agent's skill, +3 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Spying_Talent}Spying Talent
{Spying_Talent_desc}Has an ability to discover things he shouldn't know. Be places he should not be.
{Spying_Talent_effects_desc}+2 to agent's skill
{Strategically_Sound}Strategically Sound
{Strategically_Sound_desc}This man made a point of studying strategic matters properly when given the chance.
{Strategically_Sound_effects_desc}+2 Command
{Strategist}Strategist
{Strategist_desc}This man makes grand plans and plots, his studies and natural ability to think around a situation making him a great strategist.
{Strategist_effects_desc}+3 Command
{Superb_Administrator}Superb Administrator
{Superb_Administrator_desc}This man is a natural governor, able to properly administrate the affairs of a powerful city-state.
{Superb_Administrator_effects_desc}10% bonus on all trade income, +3 to law (improves public order)
{Superb_Diplomat}Superb Diplomat
{Superb_Diplomat_desc}This man is a master mediator, able to bring reasonable resolution from a situation of spite and malice.
{Superb_Diplomat_effects_desc}+4 Influence
{Tactically_Sound}Tactically Sound
{Tactically_Sound_desc}Well schooled enough in tactical warfare enough to know how to make good use of his troops and the terrain.
{Tactically_Sound_effects_desc}+3 Command when ambushing, +2 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Tactician}Tactician
{Tactician_desc}This man's knowledge of battle tactics is thorough and complete. He has an answer for most things on the battlefield.
{Tactician_effects_desc}+4 Command when ambushing, +3 to line of sight (increases the range at which enemies are spotted)
{Total_Incompetence}Total Incompetence
{Total_Incompetence_desc}Utterly clueless in administrative roles, choosing to simply make something up when asked questions.
{Total_Incompetence_effects_desc}10% penalty on all trade income
{Translator}Translator
{Translator_desc}Fluent in most major dialects throughout Europe, Asia Minor and the Middle East.
{Translator_effects_desc}+3 Influence
{Understands_Logistics}Understands Logistics
{Understands_Logistics_desc}Knows what is needed to keep an army supplied and operational.
{Understands_Logistics_effects_desc}+1 Morale for all troops on the battlefield, +10% to Movement Points (gives armies the ability to forced march)
{Undiplomatic}Undiplomatic
{Undiplomatic_desc}Utterly unable to determine what words he says will be offensive at all.
{Undiplomatic_effects_desc}-3 Influence
{Unproven_Commander}Unproven Commander
{Unproven_Commander_desc}This man is yet little to show signs of ever being effective or confident in command.
{Unproven_Commander_effects_desc}-1 Command
{Useless_Commander}Useless Commander
{Useless_Commander_desc}This man's troops say at least two prayers before entering battle - he seems destined to command his armies to their doom.
{Useless_Commander_effects_desc}-5 Command
{Very_Diplomatic}Very Diplomatic
{Very_Diplomatic_desc}Adept at making an awkwardly delicate problem far more comfortable to talk through.
{Very_Diplomatic_effects_desc}+3 Influence
{Worthy_Admiral}Worthy Admiral
{Worthy_Admiral_desc}This man has proven that he is capable of commanding a small fleet of ships to work together in unison effectively.
{Worthy_Admiral_effects_desc}+3 Command at sea
{Would-be-Inquisitor}Would-be-Inquisitor
{Would-be-Inquisitor_desc}So swift is this man to denounce any who would follow a religion aside his chosen faith, he would likely make a great Inquisitor.
{Would-be-Inquisitor_effects_desc}-3 Influence
{Passed_Over}	Passed Over
{Passed_Over_desc}	This character was once heir to the throne, but has since lost that standing to another. The demotion has not been forgotten.
{Passed_Over_effects_desc}	-1 Loyalty
{Bitter_Claimant}	Bitter Claimant
{Bitter_Claimant_desc}	Years of watching a rival hold the position once promised to him have curdled into open resentment. He has not given up hope of reclaiming what he sees as rightfully his.
{Bitter_Claimant_effects_desc}	-2 Loyalty, -1 Influence
{Promising_Commander_gain_desc}	His performance on the battlefield has shown early promise. His fellow officers are beginning to take notice.
{Promising_Commander_lose_desc}	Whatever early promise he showed as a commander has faded from memory.
{Aspiring_Commander_gain_desc}	His grasp of battlefield tactics continues to mature. He is spoken of as an officer worth watching.
{Aspiring_Commander_lose_desc}	His reputation as a rising commander has not survived recent setbacks.
{Proven_Commander_gain_desc}	His record of victories now speaks for itself. Few doubt his ability to lead men into battle.
{Proven_Commander_lose_desc}	His once-proven record now carries considerably less weight.
{Great_Commander_gain_desc}	He is spoken of in the same breath as the great captains of the age. His campaigns are studied by his peers.
{Great_Commander_lose_desc}	His standing among the great commanders of the age has been sharply diminished.
{Legendary_Commander_gain_desc}	His name has entered the popular press and the regimental songs alike. He is, by any measure, a legend in his own time.
{Legendary_Commander_lose_desc}	Even a legend can fall. His once-untouchable reputation has been shaken.
{Legendary_Commander_epithet_desc}	the Legendary
{Useless_Commander_epithet_desc}	the Useless
{Inspirational_Speaker_epithet_desc}	the Orator
{Strategist_gain_desc}	His command of grand strategy is now widely acknowledged. Maps and dispatches alike bear the mark of his careful planning.
{Tactician_gain_desc}	On the field of battle, few can read the shifting fortunes of a fight as well as he. His tactical instincts have become the stuff of regimental legend.
{Logistician_gain_desc}	His talent for keeping an army fed, supplied, and moving has not gone unnoticed. Quartermasters across the service study his methods.
{Master_of_Diplomacy_gain_desc}	His skill at the negotiating table is now spoken of in every foreign ministry that has dealt with him. Few can match his command of diplomacy.
{Inconspicuous_gain_desc}	He has developed a talent for going unnoticed, slipping through crowds and checkpoints alike without drawing a second glance.
{Inconspicuous_lose_desc}	He no longer moves through hostile territory with the same practiced anonymity.
{Adept_Agent_gain_desc}	His fieldcraft has sharpened considerably. He can now be trusted with more delicate assignments.
{Adept_Agent_lose_desc}	His once-reliable fieldcraft has grown careless of late.
{Spy_gain_desc}	He has earned the title of spy in every sense of the word, moving through enemy territory with confidence and guile.
{Spy_lose_desc}	His reputation as a capable spy has taken a serious blow.
{Adept_Spy_gain_desc}	Few agents in the service can match his skill at extracting secrets and slipping away unseen.
{Adept_Spy_lose_desc}	His standing as one of the service's finest agents has been badly undermined.
{Master_Spy_gain_desc}	He has become a master of his trade, a name whispered with equal parts respect and fear in the intelligence circles of every rival power.
{Master_Spy_lose_desc}	Even a master spy can be exposed. His network and reputation alike lie in ruins.
{Master_Spy_epithet_desc}	the Master Spy
{Competent_Sailor_gain_desc}	He has proven himself a capable hand at sea, comfortable with the demands of naval command.
{Fine_Officer_gain_desc}	His seamanship and command of a ship's crew mark him as a fine officer of the fleet.
{Worthy_Admiral_gain_desc}	He has earned his flag many times over. The fleet trusts him without reservation.
{Great_Admiral_gain_desc}	His victories at sea have made him one of the great admirals of his generation.
{Legendary_Admiral_gain_desc}	His name is now spoken alongside the greatest admirals in naval history. Sailors the world over know of his exploits.
{Legendary_Admiral_epithet_desc}	the Legendary Admiral
{Bean_Counter_gain_desc}	He has developed a keen eye for ledgers and margins, turning a tidy profit where others might not.
{Bean_Counter_lose_desc}	His once-sharp eye for profit has dulled considerably.
{Bold_Barterer_gain_desc}	His willingness to strike bold bargains has paid off handsomely, and his reputation among trading circles has grown.
{Bold_Barterer_lose_desc}	His bold bargaining has cost him more than it has earned of late.
{Commercial_Conqueror_gain_desc}	He has built something approaching a commercial empire, outmaneuvering rivals at every turn.
{Commercial_Conqueror_lose_desc}	His commercial empire has begun to crumble under the weight of recent losses.
{Robber_Baron_gain_desc}	His ruthless business dealings have made him enormously wealthy, and enormously unpopular among those he has ruined along the way.
{Robber_Baron_lose_desc}	The empire he built through ruthless dealing has begun to collapse.
{Hidden_desc}	This is an internal characteristic and has no direct in-game description.
{Hidden_effects_desc}	 