With the manufacturing of steel and power of steam, the world was open wide to new opportunities of conquest. The British have set up colonies all across the globe, while the Americans are in the middle of a raging civil war. New powers rise elsewhere, Prussia with it's military might and the Russian Empire diving depe into Asia. In these troubled times a strong leader can mark his mark upon the world, if his ambitions are backed by military might.