¬
{Author_1}Porfirio Díaz, President of Mexico
{Author_2}Cetshwayo, King of the Zulus
{Author_3}Cetshwayo, King of the Zulus
{Author_4}Henry Hope Crealock, Lieutenant-Colonel; at Isandlwana
{Author_5}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_6}Wilhelm I, German Emperor and King of Prussia; on Bismarck
{Author_7}Patrice de MacMahon, Marshal of France
{Author_8}Patrice de MacMahon, Marshal of France; attributed remark at Malakoff, 1855
{Author_9}Patrice de MacMahon, Marshal of France
{Author_10}William McKinley, President of the United States
{Author_11}William McKinley, President of the United States; the Philippines, 1898
{Author_12}Hilarión Daza, President of Bolivia; telegram during the War of the Pacific
{Author_13}Francisco Solano López Carrillo, President of the Republic of Paraguay
{Author_14}Francisco Solano López Carrillo, President of the Republic of Paraguay
{Author_15}Victoria, Queen of the United Kingdom and Empress of India
{Author_16}Victoria, Queen of the United Kingdom and Empress of India
{Author_17}Feng Guifen, Qing official and reformer
{Author_18}Feng Guifen, Qing official and reformer
{Author_19}Feng Guifen, Qing official and reformer
{Author_20}Porfirio Díaz, President of Mexico
{Author_21}Adolphe Thiers, President of France
{Author_22}Charles Robert Darwin, English scientist
{Author_23}Alfred Thayer Mahan, American admiral and historian
{Author_24}Henry John Temple, Viscount Palmerston, British Prime Minister
{Author_25}Henry John Temple, Viscount Palmerston, British Prime Minister
{Author_26}Napoleon III, Emperor of the French
{Author_27}Henry John Temple, Viscount Palmerston, British Prime Minister
{Author_28}Napoleon III, Emperor of the French; on smoking
{Author_29}Nikolai I Pavlovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_30}Menelik II, Ethiopian King of Kings
{Author_31}Napoleon III, Emperor of the French
{Author_32}Karl Marx, German socialist philosopher; on Napoleon III’s coup (paraphrased)
{Author_33}Karl Marx, German socialist philosopher
{Author_34}Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels, "The Communist Manifesto"
{Author_35}Friedrich Engels, German socialist philosopher
{Author_36}Paul Doumer, Governor-General of French Indochina
{Author_37}Karl Marx, German socialist philosopher
{Author_38}Karl Marx, German socialist philosopher
{Author_39}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_40}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_41}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_42}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_43}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_44}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_45}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_46}Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of the German Empire
{Author_47}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, British Prime Minister
{Author_48}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, British Prime Minister
{Author_49}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, British Prime Minister
{Author_50}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, British Prime Minister
{Author_51}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, British Prime Minister
{Author_52}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, British Prime Minister
{Author_53}Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield, British Prime Minister
{Author_54}William Ewart Gladstone, British Prime Minister
{Author_55}William Ewart Gladstone, British Prime Minister
{Author_56}William Ewart Gladstone, British Prime Minister
{Author_57}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_58}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_59}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_60}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_61}Alfred Tennyson, Poet Laureate of the United Kingdom, "The Charge of the Light Brigade"
{Author_62}Henri Duval, French colonial official; rubber production in Indochina
{Author_63}Leopold I, King of the Belgians
{Author_64}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_65}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_66}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_67}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_68}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_69}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_70}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_71}Leopold II, King of the Belgians and Sovereign of the Congo Free State
{Author_72}Charles George Gordon, British general
{Author_73}Charles George Gordon, British general
{Author_74}Charles George Gordon, British general; besieged at Khartoum
{Author_75}Charles George Gordon, British officer; burning the Summer Palace, 1860
{Author_76}Henry Morton Stanley, Welsh-American explorer
{Author_77}Henry Morton Stanley, Welsh-American explorer
{Author_78}Henry Morton Stanley, Welsh-American explorer
{Author_79}Shaka kaSenzangakhona, King of the Zulu Kingdom
{Author_80}Hilaire Belloc, Franco-English writer, "The Modern Traveller"
{Author_81}Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "Land and Sea Tales" (1923)
{Author_82}Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "The White Man’s Burden"
{Author_83}Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "Tommy"
{Author_84}Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "The Grave of the Hundred Head"
{Author_85}Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "The Grave of the Hundred Head"
{Author_86}Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "The Grave of the Hundred Head"
{Author_87}Rudyard Kipling, English writer and poet, "Pharaoh and the Sergeant"
{Author_88}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_89}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_90}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_91}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_92}Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov, Emperor of all the Russias
{Author_93}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_94}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_95}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_96}Wilhelm II, German Emperor and King of Prussia
{Author_97}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria and King of Hungary
{Author_98}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria and King of Hungary
{Author_99}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria and King of Hungary
{Author_100}Franz Joseph I, Emperor of Austria and King of Hungary
{Author_101}Le Bien Public, Belgian newspaper; the Second Mexican Empire
{Author_102}United States Congress; the Second Mexican Empire
{Author_103}Maximilian I, Emperor of Mexico
{Author_104}Robert E. Lee, Confederate general
{Author_105}Robert E. Lee, Confederate general
{Author_106}Robert E. Lee, Confederate general
{Author_107}Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States
{Author_108}Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States
{Author_109}William McKinley, President of the United States
{Author_110}Thieu Tri, Emperor of Dai Nam
{Author_111}Matsudaira Katamori, Daimyō of Aizu; before defeat at the Battle of Aizu, 1868
{Author_112}Sakurai Tadayoshi, Lieutenant of the Imperial Japanese Army, "Human Bullets"
{Author_113}Đỗ Hữu Vị, Captain of the French Foreign Legion
{Author_114}Cixi, Empress Dowager of the Qing dynasty
{Author_115}Zuo Zongtang, General of the Qing dynasty
{Author_116}Liú Yǒngfú, General of the Black Flag Army
{Author_117}Charles Clive Bigham, British intelligence officer
{Author_118}Ōtori Keisuke, Commander of the Ezo army; urging surrender at Hakodate
{Author_119}Léon Roches, French consul in Japan
{Author_120}Pierre-Louis Charles de Failly, Divisional general of the French Army; after the Battle of Mentana, 1867
{Author_121}Menelik II, Ethiopian King of Kings
{Author_122}Sakuma Shōzan, Japanese scholar

{Quote_1}"It was better that a little blood should be shed that much blood should be saved. The blood that was shed was bad blood; the blood that was saved was good blood."
{Quote_2}"I am glad to know that the Transvaal is English ground; perhaps now there may be rest."
{Quote_3}"I love the English. I am the child of Queen Victoria. But I am also King in my own country and must be treated as such. Somsteu [Theophilus Shepstone] must speak gently to me. I shall not bear his dictation: I shall perish first."
{Quote_4}"How very amusing! Actually attacking our camp! Most amusing."
{Quote_5}"The poor French… They have not read their Mahan!"
{Quote_6}"It's hard to be emperor under such a chancellor."
{Quote_7}"The Legion is here. It's in the bag!"
{Quote_8}"Here I am, here I stay."
{Quote_9}"Typhoid fever is a terrible sickness. Either you die from it or you remain idiotic from it. I know what I'm talking about, I have had it."
{Quote_10}"We need Hawaii just as much and a good deal more than we did California. It is Manifest Destiny."
{Quote_11}"The mission of the United States is one of benevolent assimilation."
{Quote_12}"Desert overwhelms, army refuses to move forward."
{Quote_13}"If the remnants of my armies have followed me to this final moment, it is because they knew that I, their leader, would succumb with the last of them on this last battlefield."
{Quote_14}"The winner is not the one who stays alive on the battlefield, but the one who dies for a beautiful cause."
{Quote_15}"It is worth being shot at to see how much one is loved."
{Quote_16}"It seems to me a defect in our much famed Constitution, to have to part with an admirable Govt like Ld Salisbury's for no question of any importance…, merely on account of the number of votes."
{Quote_17}"Why are the Western nations small and yet strong? Why are we large and yet weak? We must search for the means to become their equal, and that depends solely on human effort…"
{Quote_18}"We have only one thing to learn from the barbarians, and that is strong ships and effective guns."
{Quote_19}"A great many of the foreign chiefs have learned our written and spoken language, the best of them can even read our classics and histories."
{Quote_20}"Poor Mexico, so far from God, so close to the United States."
{Quote_21}"For those who govern, the first thing required is indifference to newspapers."
{Quote_22}"An American monkey, after getting drunk on brandy, would never touch it again, and thus is much wiser than most men."
{Quote_23}"Force is never more operative than when it is known to exist but is not brandished."
{Quote_24}"The Schleswig-Holstein question is so complicated, only three men have ever understood it. One was Prince Albert, who is dead. The second was a German professor who became mad. I am the third and have forgotten all about it."
{Quote_25}"The policy and practice of the Russian Government has always been to push forward its encroachments as fast and as far as the apathy or want of firmness of other Governments would allow it to go…"
{Quote_26}"Usually, it is man who attacks; as for me, I defend myself, and I often capitulate."
{Quote_27}"We have no eternal allies, and we have no perpetual enemies. Our interests are eternal and perpetual, and those interests it is our duty to follow."
{Quote_28}"This vice brings in one hundred million francs in taxes every year. I will certainly forbid it at once - as soon as you can name a virtue that brings in as much revenue."
{Quote_29}"All I can say is that in case of a partition after the downfall of the Ottoman Empire, if you take possession of Egypt, I shall have no objections to make."
{Quote_30}"Plant the Ethiopian flag and make the inhabitants submit in all the country as far as the White Nile."
{Quote_31}"The Empress is legitimist, my cousin is Republican, Morny is Orleanist, I am a socialist; the only Bonapartist is Persigny, and he is mad."
{Quote_32}"History repeats itself, first as tragedy, second as farce."
{Quote_33}"The English have all the material requisites for the revolution. What they lack is the spirit of generalization and revolutionary ardour."
{Quote_34}"A specter is haunting Europe - the specter of communism."
{Quote_35}"Look at the Paris Commune. That was the Dictatorship of the Proletariat."
{Quote_36}"When France arrived in Indochina, the Annamites [Vietnamese] were ripe for servitude."
{Quote_37}"It is in this sense that Franklin says, 'war is robbery, commerce is generally cheating.'"
{Quote_38}"The redeeming feature of war is that it puts a nation to the test. As exposure to the atmosphere reduces mummies to instant dissolution, so war passes supreme judgment upon social systems that have outlived their vitality."
{Quote_39}"Only a fool learns from his own mistakes. The wise man learns from the mistakes of others."
{Quote_40}"One day the great European War will come out of some damned foolish thing in the Balkans."
{Quote_41}"God has a special providence for fools, drunkards, and the United States of America."
{Quote_42}"Preventive war is like committing suicide out of fear of death."
{Quote_43}"It is the destiny of the weak to be devoured by the strong."
{Quote_44}"The secret of politics? Make a good treaty with Russia."
{Quote_45}"The great questions of the day will not be settled by means of speeches and majority decisions but by iron and blood."
{Quote_46}"People never lie so much as after a hunt, during a war, or before an election."
{Quote_47}"The difference between a misfortune and a calamity is this: If Gladstone fell into the Thames, it would be a misfortune. But if someone dragged him out again, that would be a calamity."
{Quote_48}"Like all great travellers, I have seen more than I remember, and remember more than I have seen."
{Quote_49}"Everyone likes flattery; and when you come to Royalty you should lay it on with a trowel."
{Quote_50}"No Government can be long secure without a formidable Opposition."
{Quote_51}"Colonies do not cease to be colonies because they are independent."
{Quote_52}"The practice of politics in the East may be defined by one word: dissimulation."
{Quote_53}"We are bound to lose Ireland in consequence of years of cruelty, stupidity and misgovernment and I would rather lose her as a friend than as a foe."
{Quote_54}"Remember the rights of the savage, as we call him. Remember that the happiness of his humble home, the sanctity of life in the hill villages of Afghanistan is as inviolable in the eye of Almighty God, as can be your own."
{Quote_55}"All the world over, I will back the masses against the classes."
{Quote_56}"Here is my first principle of foreign policy: good government at home."
{Quote_57}"'Forward, the Light Brigade!' Was there a man dismayed? Not though the soldier knew, Someone had blundered. Theirs not to make reply, Theirs not to reason why, Theirs but to do and die."
{Quote_58}"Cannon to right of them, Cannon to left of them, Cannon in front of them. Volleyed and thundered Stormed at with shot and shell, Boldly they rode and well, Into the jaws of Death, Into the mouth of hell, Rode the six hundred."
{Quote_59}"Flashed all their sabres bare, Flashed as they turned in air. Sabring the gunners there, Charging an army, while All the world wondered."
{Quote_60}"Plunged in the battery-smoke, Right through the line they broke; Cossack and Russian, Reeled from the sabre stroke, Shattered and sundered."
{Quote_61}"When can their glory fade? O the wild charge they made! All the world wondered. Honour the charge they made! Honour the Light Brigade, Noble six hundred!"
{Quote_62}"Rubber is now king. Our production quotas are nearly met. Coolie workers are harvesting some 1,000 litres [of rubber] a day. They work, on average, 11-12 hours per day and are paid well by local conditions."
{Quote_63}"The sedition mongers are not numerous, but they frighten the peaceful majority, who, although it can be really strong, feels a veritable panic before this agitating force in the shadows?"
{Quote_64}"The Congo Free State is unique in its kind. It has nothing to hide and no secrets and is not beholden to anyone except its founder."
{Quote_65}"The mission which the agents of the State in Congo must fulfill is noble and of high purpose. Their task is the work of civilization. They must subject the population to laws, the most urgent and beneficial of which is labour."
{Quote_66}"I will give them my Congo, but they have no right to know what I did there."
{Quote_67}"It is very curious to see how in China and Morocco the vanquished pay for the costs of the expedition that crushed them."
{Quote_68}"A People which is content with its homeland and which shreds at even the shadow of a conflict lacks the characteristics of a superior race."
{Quote_69}"I have no other desire than to leave Belgium bigger, stronger and more beautiful."
{Quote_70}"I want it to be and it will be."
{Quote_71}"A battle with the Netherlands must be a surprise on our part, we must suddenly present ourselves there with weapons, disrupt the order, and keep the provinces that want to join, let the others go free as they please."
{Quote_72}"For a foreign power to take this country [the Sudan] would be most easy. The mass are far from fanatical… It is the government that needs civilizing far more than the people."
{Quote_73}"The Sudan is a useless possession, ever was so, and ever will be so…"
{Quote_74}"NOW MARK THIS—if the Expeditionary Force, and I ask for no more than 200 men, does not come in 10 days, the town may fall; and I have done the best for the honor of our country. Good Bye"
{Quote_75}"You can scarcely imagine the beauty and magnificence of the palaces we burnt. It made one’s heart sore just to burn them; those palaces were so large, and we were so pressed for time, that we could not plunder them carefully."
{Quote_76}"Doctor Livingstone, I presume?"
{Quote_77}"I have arrived at this place from Zanzibar with 115 souls, men, women & children. We are now in a state of imminent starvation. We can purchase nothing from the natives for they laugh at our kinds of cloth…"
{Quote_78}"We have attacked and destroyed 28 large towns, and 3 or 4 score villages."
{Quote_79}"I need no bodyguard at all, for even the bravest men who approach me get weak at the knees and their hearts turn to water, whilst their heads become giddy and incapable of thinking as the sweat of fear paralyzes them."
{Quote_80}"Whatever happens, we have got, the Maxim gun, and they have not."
{Quote_81}"Nations have passed away and left no traces, And history gives the naked cause of it - One single simple reason in all cases; They fell because their peoples were not fit."
{Quote_82}"Take up the white man's burden - Send forth the best ye breed - Go bind your sons to exile To serve your captives' need."
{Quote_83}"For it's Tommy this an' Tommy that, and 'Chuck 'im out, the brute.' But it's 'Savior of 'is country,' when the guns begin to shoot."
{Quote_84}"A Snider squibbed in the jungle, Somebody laughed and fled, And the men of the First Shikaris Picked up their Subaltern dead; With a big blue mark in his forehead And the back blown out of his head."
{Quote_85}"The men of the First Shikaris, Shouted and smote and slew, Turning the grinning jingal On to the howling crew. The Jemadar's flanking-party Butchered the folk who flew."
{Quote_86}"Then a silence came to the river, A hush fell over the shore, And Bohs that were brave departed, And Sniders squibbed no more; For the Burmans said That a white man's head Must be paid for with heads five-score."
{Quote_87}"Said England unto Pharaoh, ‘I must make a man of you, That will stand upon his feet and play the game; That will Maxim his oppressor as a Christian ought to do,’ And she sent old Pharaoh Sergeant Whatsisname."
{Quote_88}"I am not yet ready to be Tsar. I know nothing of the business of ruling."
{Quote_89}"All around me is cowardice and deceit."
{Quote_90}"Our blockheads have decided to celebrate the day by parading in the streets with bands of music and red flags."
{Quote_91}"I do not rule Russia: Ten thousand clerks do."
{Quote_92}"I will preserve the principle of Autocracy as firmly and unflinchingly as my late father."
{Quote_93}"You [recruits] have sworn loyalty to me. You have only one enemy and that is my enemy. It may come about that I order you to shoot down your own relatives, brothers or parents… you must follow my orders without a murmur."
{Quote_94}"No quarter will be given! Prisoners will not be taken! Whoever falls into your hands is forfeited. Just as a thousand years ago the Huns under their King Attila made a name for themselves…"
{Quote_95}"The Tsar is not treacherous but he is weak. Weakness is not treachery, but it fulfils all its functions."
{Quote_96}"Shoot down, behead and eliminate the Socialists first, if need be, by a blood-bath, then war abroad."
{Quote_97}"Now we can no longer hold back. It will be a terrible war."
{Quote_98}"I am the last ruler of the old world."
{Quote_99}"My policy is a policy of peace. Everybody should take note of that."
{Quote_100}"People say about me: He is old by now, nor does he understand. Then revolutions will break out and it will all be over."
{Quote_101}"In a very short time, the monarchy will be so firmly established in Mexico, that one will only be surprised not to have tried it sooner."
{Quote_102}"Congress declares that it cannot recognize the founding of a monarchy on the ruins of a Mexican republic with the help of a European power."
{Quote_103}"I forgive everyone, and I ask everyone to forgive me. May my blood, which is about to be shed, be for the good of the country. ¡Viva México, viva la independencia!"
{Quote_104}"It is well that war is so terrible, or we should grow too fond of it."
{Quote_105}"I like whiskey. I always did, and that is why I never drink it."
{Quote_106}"The consolidation of the states into one vast empire, sure to be aggressive abroad and despotic at home, will be the certain precursor of ruin which has overwhelmed all that preceded it."
{Quote_107}"War at the best, is terrible, and this war of ours, in its magnitude and in its duration, is one of the most terrible."
{Quote_108}"Without slavery the rebellion could never have existed; without slavery it could not continue."
{Quote_109}"Cuba ought to be free and independent, and the government should be turned over to the Cuban people."
{Quote_110}"The French are truly a gang of barbarians. Their crimes cannot be pardoned. Any commercial or military ship coming to our shores should be chased away… Erect more fortifications and artillery of all kinds."
{Quote_111}"No matter how many tens of thousands of enemies there are, our elite troops of Aizu will annihilate them all at once."
{Quote_112}"When this gallant assaulting column had pressed upon the enemy's forts, stepping over their comrades' bodies, the terrible and skillful fire of the machine guns had killed them all, close by the forts, piling the dead upon the wounded."
{Quote_113}"I must be doubly courageous, for I am both a Frenchman and an Annamite."
{Quote_114}"[The westerners] have started the aggression and the extinction of our nation is imminent. If we just fold our arms and yield to them, I would have no face to see our ancestors after death. If we must perish, why not fight to the death?"
{Quote_115}"We shall first confront [the Russians] with arguments… and then settle it on the battlefield."
{Quote_116}"If you [French] are afraid to come… Then give back the cities you have taken. I am a merciful commander, and I will let you miserable ants live. But if you delay, my army will take your city and kill you all, and not even a blade of grass will mark where you stood."
{Quote_117}"The German officer in command of the troops left at Langfang, was attacked by the Imperial forces belonging to General Tung-fuh-siang's [Gansu Braves] division. Their numbers were estimated at 7,000 and they were well armed with modern rifles which they used with effect, so that we suffered considerable casualties."
{Quote_118}"If it's dying you want, you can do it anytime."
{Quote_119}"The character of the Japanese essentially distinguishes them from other oriental people… We must act towards them with goodwill and dignity, critically but with justice; we can often appeal to their sentiment of honour and to the pride found among all of them, even among the lowest classes…"
{Quote_120}"The Chassepots have done wonderfully!"
{Quote_121}"Ethiopia has been for fourteen centuries a Christian island in a sea of pagans."
{Quote_122}"Eastern ethics, Western science."
